A Finding Aid to the Ruth Bowman Papers, 1936-2006, bulk 1963-1999, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bowmruth2
Archives of American Art
Ruth Bowman papers
bulk 1963-1999
1936-2006
AAA.bowmruth2
Archives of American Art
21.1 Linear feet
The papers of art historian and museum educator Ruth Bowman are dated 1936-2006, bulk 1963-1999, and measure 21.1 linear feet. Professional correspondence and subject files document Bowman's relationships with colleagues and reflect her interests, activities including curatorial work, and accomplishments as a museum educator. Writings and related research materials include her thesis,"Thomas Pollock Anshutz, 1851-1912" (M.A., Institute of Fine Arts, New York University, 1971), and unfinished projects. Also found are interviews conducted by Bowman with a wide range of individuals for a variety of purposes.
Bowman, Ruth, 1923-
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 5 series:
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1964-1984 (Box 1; 0.1 linear feet)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1963-1996 (Box 1; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 3: Writings and Related Research, 1942-1999 (Boxes 1-3; 1.5 linear feet)
Series 4: Subject Files, 1936-2006 (Boxes 3-12, 26; 9.6 linear feet)
Series 5: Interviews, 1963-1989 (Boxes 12-25; 9.2 linear feet)
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Donated by Ruth Bowman in 2004.
Biographical/Historical note
Ruth Bowman (b. 1923) is an art historian and museum educator who worked in New York City and Los Angeles. She is known for her interest in using new communications technology for museum education, discovering Arshile Gorky's long forgotten murals at Newark Airport, and expertise in the work of Thomas Anshutz.
A graduate of Bryn Mawr College (B.A. 1944), where she had studied art history and classical archaeology, Ruth Bowman began a museum career in New York as an assistant curator at the Jewish Museum in the early 1960s. From 1963-1974 Ruth Bowman served as curator of the York University Art Collection and was involved in its transition to the Grey Art Gallery and Study Center. Bowman wrote her master's thesis on Philadelphia artist Thomas Pollock Anshutz and received a degree from the Institute of Fine Arts, New York University in 1971. During this same period, she was a staff lecturer at The Museum of Modern Art and taught art history in divisions of New York University. She was the instructor for a "Sunrise Semester" 20th century American art course broadcast nationally on CBS.
In 1974 Bowman and her family moved to California and she began an association with the Los Angeles County Museum of Art as Director of Education. She attended summer courses in arts administration at Harvard University (1975) and similar training provided by the British Arts Council (1976). She taught at University of California Santa Barbara, as well as at California State University at Fullerton and Long Beach. Bowman was active in the Council of the American Association of Museums (vice president), the Craft and Folk Art Museum in Los Angeles (vice president), and has served as a consultant to several museums and a corporate collection.
Ruth Bowman with her friend Harry Kahn (1916-1999) developed a collection of self-portraits by 20th century American artists, which she donated to the National Portrait Gallery in 2002. Mrs. Bowman is the widow of R. Wallace Bowman and currently resides in New York City.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of art historian and museum educator Ruth Bowman are dated 1936-2006, bulk 1963-1999, and measure 21.1 linear feet. Professional correspondence and subject files document Bowman's relationships with colleagues and reflect her interests, activities including curatorial work, and accomplishments as a museum educator. Writing and related research materials include her thesis, "Thomas Pollock Anshutz, 1851-1912" (M.A., Institute of Fine Arts, New York University, 1971), and unfinished projects. Also found are interviews conducted by Bowman with a wide range of individuals for a variety of purposes.
Biographical materials consist of certificates, resumes, and a few photographs of Ruth Bowman. Correspondence concerns Bowman's professional activities and interests. Among the most frequent correspondents are: American Association of Museums, Craft and Folk Art Museum (Los Angeles), Massachusetts Institute of Technology, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, and The Museum of Modern Art.
Writings by Ruth Bowman, published and unpublished, include a thesis and articles about Thomas Pollock Anshutz, catalogs for American Federation of Arts and The Newark Museum exhibitions, lectures, as well as articles about museum education and visual arts programs. Research relates to her writings about Anshutz, and to unrealized projects concerning Anshutz, Cézanne, Eakins, Picasso, and other subjects. Also found are two brief writings about Bowman.
Subject files--general subjects, artists' files, Ruth Bowman activities, and "Sunrise Semester"--contain the majority of Bowman's professional correspondence along with printed material, writings, photographs, and sound recordings. Among the most thoroughly documented general subjects are: The Brooklyn Museum's Trustees Retreat, Canadian Museums Association, a 1981 Craft Symposium, International Network for the Arts, Long Beach Museum of Art, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, "Museum Directors' Forum", New York University Art Collection, and Massachusetts Institute of Technology Council for the Arts. Artists' files are comprised mainly of printed material with a small amount of correspondence and some photographs. The Les Levine file consists of the first issue of Art-Rite featuring a brief article about Levine on its cover; Thomas Wilfred's file includes information about Lumia. Ruth Bowman activities include lectures, radio and television appearances, and participation in professional events. "Sunrise Semester," a collaboration between CBS television and New York University, offered early morning courses for college credit. Ruth Bowman was the instructor for "20th Century American Art," which is documented by general information, scripts, and sound recordings of all 46 classes.
Interviews conducted by Bowman are with English museum administrators and educators; people knowledgeable about a controversial proposal for an Annenberg Fine Arts Center at The Metropolitan Museum of Art; guests on KUSC radio shows "Sounds of Seeing" and "Live from Trump's"; and guests on the WNYC radio program "Views on Art." Interviews with miscellaneous individuals include Josef Albers, Hans Burkhardt, Carl Holty, Isamu Noguchi, and Helen Farr Sloan. Bowman interviewed a dozen American abstract artists, including Ilya Bolotowsky, Rosalind Bengelsdorf Browne, Burgoyne Diller, John Ferren, Carl Holty, Harry Holtzman, Ibram Lassaw, Jacques Lipchitz, Alice Mason, George McNeil, George L. K. Morris, and Ad Reinhardt for a thesis on the subject, but eventually wrote on a different topic. Two interviews with Bowman were conducted by Duncan MacDonald and an unidentified interviewer.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Albers, Josef; American Association of Museums.; American Federation of Arts.; Anshutz, Thomas Pollock, 1851-1912; Bengelsdorf, Rosalind, 1916-1979; Bolotowsky, Ilya, 1907-1981; Brooklyn Museum.; Burkhardt, Hans Gustav, 1904-1994; Canadian Museums Association.; Craft and Folk Art Museum.; Cézanne, Paul, 1839-1906; Diller, Burgoyne, 1906-1965; Eakins, Thomas, 1844-1916; Ferren, John, 1905-1970; Holty, Carl, 1900-1973; Holtzman, Harry; KUSC (Radio station: Los Angeles, Calif.).; Lassaw, Ibram, 1913-2003; Levine, Les, 1935-; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973; Long Beach Museum of Art.; Los Angeles County Museum of Art; MacDonald, Duncan, Broadcaster; Mason, Alice Trumbull, 1904-1971; Massachusetts Institute of Technology.; McNeil, George, 1908-1995; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.).; Morris, George L. K. 1905-1975; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.).; New York University; Newark Museum; Noguchi, Isamu, 1904-1988; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973; Reinhardt, Ad, 1913-1967; Sloan, Helen Farr, 1911-; Wilfred, Thomas, 1889-1968; WNYC (Radio station: New York, N.Y.).; Art historians--California--Los Angeles; Art historians--New York (State)--New York; Art, American--20th century; Art--Study and teaching; Interviews; Photographs; Scripts (documents); Sound recordings
- Biographical Materials, 1964-1984; Series 1; 0.1 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Certificates recognize completion of "Museum Education" and "Interpretation and Presentation" seminars sponsored by the American Association of Museums. Photographs are of Bowman; most show her at work, in her office, and presenting gallery talks.
  - Certificates, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1964-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Resumes, 1965-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1963-1996; Series 2; 0.7 Linear feet Box 1
  Although this is professional correpondence, there is personal content in some letters to and from colleagues with whom she was friendly.
  Arrangement note
  This series is alphabetized by correspondent. Folders were established for correspondents represented by five or more letters; all others are categorized as "miscellaneous" and filed with the appropriate letter of the alphabet. Because filing is inconsistent, researchers are advised to search by both correspondent's name and institutional affiliation. The bulk of Bowman's correspondence is found among the subject files (series 4) and, to a lesser extent, with her writings and related research (series 3).
  - A, Miscellaneous, 1964-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Association of Museums, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - B, Miscellaneous, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - C, Miscellaneous, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Clark, Jean, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Craft and Folk Art Museum, Los Angeles, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - D, Miscellaneous, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - E, Miscellaneous, 1967-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Eastman, Lee and Monique, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - F, Miscellaneous, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - G, Miscellaneous, 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Goddard-Riverside Community Center, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - H, Miscellaneous, 1967-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hebrew Union College-Jewish Institute of Religion, 1963-1979 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - I, Miscellaneous, 1975-1986 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - J, Miscellaneous, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - K, Miscellaneous, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - L, Miscellaneous, 1967-1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - M, Miscellaneous, 1973-1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The Museum of Modern Art, 1974-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - N, Miscellaneous, 1967-1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - O, Miscellaneous, 1976-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - P, Miscellaneous, 1967-1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Queens Museum, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - R, Miscellaneous, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Rush, Cynthia, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - S, Miscellaneous, 1974-1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - T, Miscellaneous, 1973-1982 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Tucker, Jean, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - U, Miscellaneous, 1967-1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - V, Miscellaneous, 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - W, Miscellaneous, 1974-1996 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Wechsler, Judith, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Y-Z, Miscellaneous, 1974-1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Unidentified (Alan - Verna; illegible), 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Writings and Related Research, 1942-1999; Series 3; 1.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-3
  This series is comprised mainly of published and unpublished writings by Ruth Bowman and related research materials pertaining to writings and contemplated projects that did not progress beyond research. Subjects include Thomas Pollock Anshutz, research on Cezanne, Thomas Eakins, Picasso, and miscellaneous topics.
  Bowman first researched Anshutz for a student paper before deciding on her thesis subject, "Thomas Pollock Anshutz, 1851-1912" (Institute of Fine Arts, New York University, 1971). Notes and correspondence for the paper and thesis further expanded as she prepared articles and lectures, planned an exhibition, and began researching a catalogue raisonne. Much of the correspondence is with owners of paintings by Anshutz and includes requests for Bowman's opinions about unsigned works. Also included are many photographs, printed material, and photocopies of archival documents. A file titled "Addenda" contains information that became available after the thesis was completed.
  Cezanne research was conducted for an article on the relationship between Cezanne's Nudes in a Landscape and Picasso's Des Demoiselles d'Avignon. Picasso research correspondence indicates Bowman was working on an article on the evolution of Picasso's early style; other letters focus on Des Demoiselles d'Avigon and are related to her Cezanne research. Miscellaneous topics concern Bowman's work as a curator of "Double Exposure" and "Murals Without Walls: Arshile Gorky's Aviation Murals Rediscovered." Other research concerns Barnes Lectures delivered at the New York University Club, the paintings of Vivienne Wechter, and notes for a brief article or catalog entry on Prendergast.
  Writings by other authors are about Bowman.
  Additional writings by Bowman and other authors are found among the subject files (series 4).
  - By Bowman (Box 1)
    - Thomas Pollock Anshutz (Box 1)
      - Addenda, 1950-1998 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Article, Art Journal, circa 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 42-44)
      - Article, Register of the Museum of Art, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Bibliography, circa 1970-circa 1972 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Correspondence, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 47-50)
      - Exhibition, 1942-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Lecture, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Notes, circa 1970-circa 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3-8)
      - Permissions, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Photographs of Artwork by Anshutz and Images of Him, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
      - Research Materials, 1963-circa 1973 (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
      - Slides of Artwork by Anshutz, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Slides of Artwork by Others, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Slides of Photographs by and of Anshutz, 1970s (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Student Paper, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Thesis, "Thomas Pollock Anshutz, 1851-1912," Institute of Fine Arts, New York University, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
    - Cezanne Research (Box 2)
      - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Notes, circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Photographs, circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Research Materials, 1947-1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Eakins Research (Box 3)
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
      - Discussion with Lloyd Goodrich, 1973 March 19; 1 Sound cassettes (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Photographs, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Printed Material, circa 1944 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Picasso Research (Box 3)
      - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Notes, circa 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Photographs, circa 1971 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Printed Material, circa 1971-1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Topics (Box 3)
      - Barnes Lectures, circa 1966; 2 sound tape reels (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Double Exposure, American Federation of Arts, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Murals Without Walls: Arshile Gorky's Aviation Murals Rediscovered, The Newark Museum, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Museum Education Research, Non-print Media Committee Notes, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Museum News Article, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - "Notes on Programs in the Visual Arts in Student Centers", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - "The Poetic Image" (Vivienne Wechter), circa 1961-circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Maurice Prendergast, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - About Bowman (Box 3)
    - Introductory Remarks about Ruth Bowman by Kay Stratton, Cosmopolitan Club Members Luncheon, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "The Singular Passion of Ruth Bowman" by Amy Wallach, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Subject Files, 1936-2006; Series 4; 9.6 Linear feet Boxes 3-13, 26
  General subjects and artists' files are alphabetized by folder rtitle. Ruth Bowman activities are filed chronologically. Sunrise Semester files are alphabetized by folder title, followed by recordings of classes, arranged chronologically.
  Subject files reflect Bowman's professional interests, memberships, and activities. They contain varying combinations of correspondence, printed material, photographs, writings, and some audiovisual material. Among the most thoroughly documented subjects are: The Brooklyn Museum's Trustees Retreat, Canadian Museums Association, a 1981 Craft Symposium, International Network for the Arts, Long Beach Museum of Art, Los Angeles County Museum of Art, Museum Directors' Forum, New York University Art Collection, and Massachusetts Institute of Technology Council for the Arts at MIT. Almost all items dated prior to 1962 and after 1999 are printed material.
  General subjects are those files measuring less than 0.5 linear feet.; included are 38 sound cassettes and 6 videocassettes (2 VHS, 4 U-Matic). Artists' files are comprised mainly of printed material with a small amount of correspondence and some photographs. The Les Levine file consists of the first issue of Art-Rite that featured on its cover "Found Object," a brief article by Levine. Also of note is Thomas Wilfred's file with information about Lumia, including material prepared by the Art Institute of Light, West Nyack, New York. The largest file, David Smith, contains mostly photocopied archival materials. Ruth Bowman's many professional activities are documented by a variety of printed materials. "Sunrise Semester," the first collaboration between network television (CBS) and a university (New York University), from 1957-1983 offered early morning televised courses for college credit. Ruth Bowman was the instructor for "Twentieth Century American Art," broadcast September 1972-January 1973. Scripts consist of slide lists for each class; recordings of all 46 classes are included (46 sound tape reels).
  - General Subjects, circa 1950s-1997 (Box 3)
    - Acoustiguide, 1980-1984; undated; 1965 (Box 3, Folder 20-21)
      includes 6 sound cassettes
    - Alliance of California Arts Councils, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - American Abstract Artists, 1966-1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - American Association of Museums Annual Conference, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - American Association of Museums Commission on Museums for a New Century, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - American Association of Museums Trustees Committee Meetings, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - American Association of Museums Trustees Conferences, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - American Council for the Arts, 1978-1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1969-1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Annenberg Fine Arts Center, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Archives of American Art California Oral History Project, 1973-1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Archives of American Art Los Angeles Center, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Archives of American Art Newsletters and Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1972-1987 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Art Museum Association of America, 1985-circa 1990 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - ARTnews World Art Market Conference, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Art Purchases, 1967-1991 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Art Table, Inc., 1987-1990; Includes 2 sound cassettes (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Arts for Communities Conference, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Association of Historians of American Art, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Bank Street College of Education, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - The Barnes Foundation, circa 1950s-circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "Beyond the Object: Planning the Appropriate Use of Non-print Media in Exhibitions", 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Bits and Bytes," Canadian Public Television, circa 1983; 3 Sound cassettes (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - The Brooklyn Museum of Art, 1987; includes 5 sound cassettes (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Brooklyn Museum Trustees Retreat, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
    - California Confederation of the Arts, 1981-1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Canadian Museums Association, circa 1960s-1985 (Box 4, Folder 14-16)
    - Children's Museums, 1975-1986 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "The Collecting of Prints: A Course in Print Connoisseurship", 1973 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - College Art Association, 1985-1986; 1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Coming to Our Senses," A Progress Report of the Arts, Education and Americans, Inc., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Conferences and Seminars, 1970-1976 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Conservation of Basketry and Textiles, circa 1963-circa 1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Craft Symposium, 1981; 10 Sound cassettes (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
    - Davis, Douglas, 1974-1984 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Design, 1964-1985 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Development of College and University Art Collections, 1969-1974 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Development of Museum Programs, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Virginia Dickensen, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "Drawing as a Language," Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - "Extended Uses for Television and Radio Productions," Diane Eisenberg, Director, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Diane Ferris Gallery, 1983-1986 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Films, 1975-1984 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Finch College Museum of Art, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Gallery Passport Ltd. Tours, 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - J. Paul Getty Trust Database and Correspondence, 1980-1984 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Gorky Murals at Newark Airport and photocopy of "My Murals for the Newark Airport: An Interpretation" (1936), 1976-1979; Oversized material housed in Box 5, Folder 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Great Art Collections", 1969-1971; includes 3 sound tape reels (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - The Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Hamilton, Fowler, 1979-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Hauser, Rick, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Helpful Hints for Art Collections, 1971; 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Hunter College, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Inocencio, David, circa 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Institute for the Study of Art in Education, 1964-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Institute in Arts Administration, Harvard University, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Institute of Fine Arts, 1970-1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Institute of International Education, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Institute of Museum Services, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Institute of the Federal Theatre Project and New Deal Culture, George Mason University, 1979-1985 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - International Association of Art Critics, 1978-1985 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - International Network for the Arts, 1976-1984 (Box 5, Folder 16-18)
    - Izen, Marhsall, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - The Jewish Museum, 1960-1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - KUSC General Information, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - KUSC "Live from Trump's", 1985 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - KUSC "Sounds of Seeing" (Box 5)
      - Current Programs, Messages, Mail Follow-up, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - General Information, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Letters from Interviewees and Listeners, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      - NEA Grant Request, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Program Research, 1980-1985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      - Program Research, Benjamin Franklin Armonica, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 28)